christianbook.com 2019-04-19

# Privacy Notice & Policy - Christianbook.com

This Privacy Policy was last updated on January 15, 2019. The previous version of the Privacy Policy can be found **here**.

Christianbook, LLC (Christianbook.com) respects the privacy of users of our website and mobile apps, including the CBD Reader, and is committed to disclosing our data collection practices so that users of our website can understand what information is collected and how it is used.

This Privacy Policy describes what information we collect from users of our website and mobile apps, including the CBD Reader, how the information we collect is used, under what circumstances we disclose the information we collect, and our users’ choices regarding the information we collect and how it is used and disclosed.

Your use of this website and mobile apps, including the CBD Reader, including visiting any page which is a part of this website and reading eBooks on the CBD Reader, constitutes your acceptance of the terms and conditions of this Privacy Policy.

**Information we collect**

Information is received and collected automatically from you and any devices, including mobile devices, you use each time you visit the Christianbook.com site. We receive and collect your Internet Protocol (IP) address, geolocation data, the browser and operating system you are utilizing, the date and time of your visit, the pages of the site which you visit, the Internet address of the website from which you linked to our site and any promotion identifiers contained in these links, and the Internet address of any website to which you link from our site. If you maintain an account with Christianbook.com and log onto the site using such account information, we also receive and collect your user identification number, user name, and password.

We use cookies, web beacons, unique identifiers, and other similar technologies, including Google Analytics, each time you visit our site to collect information about the pages you view, the links you click, and other actions you take when using our services, reviewing our advertising, or communicating with us by email.

Cookies are small files, which are usually made up of letters and numbers, which are placed in the memory of the browser or device you are using and which allow a website to recognize a particular browser or device. There are different types of cookies. Session cookies allow us to track your action during a particular browsing session and they expire at the end of a browsing session. Persistent cookies allow us to remember and track your preferences and actions across various websites and different browsing sessions and are stored in your device in between particular browsing sessions. First party cookies are placed by the website you are visiting. Third party cookies are placed by a third party website separate from the website you are currently visiting.

Most commercial browsers provide tools that allow you to disable or remove cookies. You will need to set your preferences regarding cookies and otherwise separately for each commercial browser you use as different browsers have different functionality and options.

Web beacons are small graphic files, also known as pixel tags or clear GIFs that we may include on our website, services, applications, messaging, and tools. Web beacons typically work in conjunction with cookies to identify and track our users and actions taken by our users.

We use other similar technologies that store information on your browser or device by using local shared objects or local storage such as flash cookies, HTML 5 cookies, and other web application software methods. These technologies may operate across all of your browsers and you may not be able to manage these technologies through your browser but will have to manage them directly through your installed applications or device.   
We may use the terms "cookies" or "similar technologies" interchangeably in our policies to refer to all technologies that we may use to store data in your browser or device or that collect information or help us identify you in the manner described above.

We use cookies, web beacons and similar technologies for the following general purposes:

  * Operational Necessity. We may use cookies, web beacons and similar technologies that are necessary for the operation of our website, services, application and tools including allowing you to access such websites, services, applications and tools; that allow us to identify irregular behavior on our website, prevent fraudulent activity, and improve our website security; and, that allow you to make use of certain functions on our website such as shopping carts, saved searches, and similar functions
  * Performance Assessment and Enhancement. We may use cookies, web beacons and similar technologies to assess and enhance the performance of our website, services, applications and tools
  * Functionality Assessment and Enhancement. We may use cookies, web beacons and similar technologies to assess and enhance the functionality of our website, services, applications and tools including identifying you when you access or sign onto our website and tracking your particular preferences, interests, and shopping history
  * Advertising and Targeted Marketing. We may use cookies, web beacons and similar technologies to assess and determine particular content to be delivered to you including advertising and marketing relevant to your particular interests on both our website and on third party websites 

In the following instances, we may require you to submit personally identifiable information which we receive and collect: (1) open an account; (2) complete and submit an order on our site or from our catalogs; (3) request a catalog; (4) submit a customer review; (5) create a registry with a Gift Registry Service; (6) enter a contest; (7) communicate with customer service; (8) conduct a search; or (9) subscribe to a newsletter or customer alert. The information which we may receive and collect in connection with any of these activities includes your name, address, telephone number, fax number, and email address; credit card information; names and addresses of the parties to whom product is shipped; content of reviews and emails sent to us; and, your password.

We also receive and collect certain information when you communicate to us by telephone, mail, fax, or email. We may request and receive a confirmation from you when you receive and open an email from us.

We receive and collect personal information from third parties which we add to your account information such as collecting and using demographic and other publically available information, adding additional contact information, and checking and reviewing credit information in accordance with applicable laws. “Do Not Track” – Some commercial browsers allow the user to send a “Do Not Track” signal to websites. Under California law, we are required to inform you how our website responds to such “Do Not Track” signals. There are currently no industry, technology, or legal standards for how websites recognize and honor “Do Not Track” signals. Accordingly, this website does not respond to browser-based “Do Not Track” requests.

**How the information we collect is used**

We use the information which we collect from you internally for the following purposes: process, track, and fulfill your order; communicate with you regarding your order; create a gift certificate; respond to a request for information; send you catalogs or promotional information and material; send you newsletters, customer alerts, and email; communicate with you regarding products you have purchased; improve our website; enhance our customer service; track customer preferences; and, improve and enhance our product selection.

We do not sell or otherwise provide the information we collect from you to third parties except asdescribed below.

We share information with our subsidiary and affiliated companies which are owned or controlled by us or which are under common ownership and control with us.

We also share information with third party companies, service providers, agents, and subcontractors which are not our subsidiary or affiliated companies including the following categories of companies:

  * Search Engines such as Google and Bing 
  * Social Networking sites such as Facebook, Twitter and Instagram 
  * Professional mailing list companies 
  * Printers of our catalogs and other promotional and advertising materials 
  * Mailing list rentals, exchanges and co-ops 
  * Credit Card processing companies 
  * Online payment services 
  * Postal and delivery services 
  * Fulfillment services 
  * Data analysis companies 
  * Market research companies 
  * Technology infrastructure providers 
  * Marketing, promotional, advertising, and remarketing service providers 
  * Personalization and recommendation services 
  * Tax compliance and automation services 
  * Companies related to the fulfillment of eBook purchases including DRM applications and reporting to content providers 
  * Publishers of subscription magazines 

If you visit a third party website that is operated and maintained by us on behalf of such third parties, your personal information may be shared with such third party. These websites may be identified by the inclusion of the third party’s name in the URL such as www.thirdparty.christianbook.com where “third party” would be replaced by the name or other identifier of the third party.

We may provide our mailing list (names, addresses, and/or email addresses) and information about individual shopping interests to other select companies whose products or services may be of interest to you. We may also send you catalogs or other promotional materials on behalf of other companies. See “What Are My Choices Regarding My Information?” below for your options regarding these other companies.

We may in the future sell some or all of our assets and/or business units, in which case, customer information may be one of the assets transferred. 

We may disclose any information that we collect if required by law or valid order of a court or other governmental authority or to protect the health and safety of our employees or the general public. 

**How is the information secured?**

Sensitive information which we receive and collect from you is secured using encryption technology such as Transportation Layer Security (TLS) technology. This technology prevents information which is transmitted over the Internet from being intercepted and read by unauthorized parties. All information is stored on secured computers to which access is restricted.

**How can I access my information?**

Personal information can be accessed by logging onto Your Account Page of our site. You may also track orders and recent account activity.

**What are my choices regarding my information?**

You can review, modify, update, and delete certain information contained in Your Account by logging onto Your Account page of our site.

If you do not wish to receive promotional emails from us, you can indicate this by changing Your Email Preferences in the Account section of the Christianbook.com website or by sending an email to "unsubscribe@christianbook.com" with the word "unsubscribe" included in the subject field or by calling us toll free at 1-800-CHRISTIAN (1-800-247-4784, US and Canada; 1-978-977-5000 all other countries), or by writing us at CBD Mail Preference Service, P.O. Box 7000, Peabody, MA 01961-7000. (Please specify in your correspondence that you do not want to receive future email notices from CBD.)

If you wish to be removed from our mailing list, please send an email to "customer.service@christianbook.com", call us at 1-800-CHRISTIAN (1-800-247-4784, US and Canada; 1-978-977-5000 all other countries), or write to us at CBDMail Preference Service, P.O. Box 7000, Peabody, MA 01961-7000. Please specify in your correspondence that you do not wish to receive mailings from CBD.

If you prefer that we do not share any of your information with other companies, you can indicate this by sending an email to us at "customer.service@christianbook.com", by calling us at 1-800-CHRISTIAN (1-800-247-4784, US and Canada; 1-978-977-5000 all other countries), or by writing to us at CBD Mail Preference Service, PO Box 7000, Peabody, MA 01961-7000. Please specify in your correspondence that you do not want us to share your address with other companies. If you are already receiving unwanted mailings, please provide us with your exact name and address. 

If you do not wish to receive catalogs, emails, or other promotional materials from other companies, you can indicate this by sending an email to us at "customer.service@christianbook.com", by calling us at 1-800-CHRISTIAN (1-800-247-4784, US and Canada; 1-978-977-5000 all other countries), or by writing to us at CBD Mail Preference Service, PO Box 7000, Peabody, MA 01961-7000. Please specify in your correspondence that you do not want us to share your address with other companies. If you are already receiving unwanted mailings, please provide us with your exact name and address.

If you purchase products or services from our site without opening an account, you may indicate that you do not wish to receive catalogs, emails, or other communications from us or from other companies during the purchase ordering process.

Please see “Information We Collect”, above, for information on how to set your browser to deal with Cookies.

**Underage Users**

If you are under the age of eighteen (18) years, you may use this web site and purchase products and services through the use of this web site only with the involvement and under the supervision of a parent or legal guardian.

**Links to other websites and third-party advertisers**

Our site includes links to other websites, some of which may not be our subsidiary or affiliated companies and we are not responsible for their actions or activities. We encourage you to review the privacy and security policies of these websites and advertisers. 

**Conditions of use**

Your use of this website and the purchase of products and services through this website are subject to the terms and conditions of this Privacy Policy and the Terms of Use Agreement which is available **here**. 

**Changes to Privacy Policy**

Christianbook.com reserves the right, in its sole discretion, to modify and amend this Privacy Policy in any manner at any time by posting a change notice or new Privacy Policy on our website.

**FOR EU AND EEA CUSTOMERS ONLY**

We recognize and respect our EU and EEA customers’ rights to access, correct, request the deletion of, and/or request that our use of your personal information be restricted in accordance with applicable law. We also strive to ensure that the personal information we collect is and remains accurate and up to date.

Your rights subject to applicable law regarding your personal information include:

  * The right to know what personal information we maintain about you
  * The right to be provided a copy of your personal information in a commonly used and machine readable format upon your written request
  * The right to request that any incorrect, incomplete or out of date information be corrected and/or updated
  * The right to object to the processing of your personal information
  * The right to request that your personal information be deleted or to request restrictions on how we use this personal information (this right is determined and could be restricted by applicable law and may impact your ability to access and/or use some of our services)

You can review, modify, update, and delete certain personal information by logging onto Your Account page of our site. You should updateyour information immediately if it changes or is inaccurate or incomplete. If you make a public posting, you may not be able to change or remove it.

We will comply with any right you may have under applicable law to access, modify, erase, or restrict the use of your personal information. To request access to your personal information, to request that your personal information be modified, to request that your personal information be erased, or to request that the use of your personal information be restricted, please send an email to privacyrequest@cbd.com and include in your email your first and last name, your site user name, your email address, your country of residence, and a description of your request regarding your personal information. Please include in the subject line of your email: “EU Privacy Request”. You should be aware that fees may apply if permitted by applicable law. Where you have a right under applicable law to request access to your personal information, to request that your personal information be modified, to request that your personal information be erased, or to request that the use of your personal information be restricted, we may have the right to decline such access or to deny your request regarding the modification, erasure, or restriction on the use of your personal information in accordance with and as allowed by applicable law.

If you request that the processing of some or all of your personal information be terminated or you withdraw your consent, where applicable, to our use and disclosure of your personal information for the purposes explained in this privacy notice, we may not be able to offer you all of the services and customer support which we provide to our authorized users and customers.

When requested, we will close your account and remove your personal information from view as soon as reasonably possible based on recent account activity and in accordance with applicable law.

You are contracting with Christianbook, LLC, of 140 Summit Street, Peabody, Massachusetts 01960 USA. The company you are contracting with is your data controller, and is responsible for the collection, use, disclosure, retention and protection of your personal information in accordance with this privacy notice and applicable law. When required by applicable law, we have appointed a Data Protection Officer to be responsible for this privacy policy.
